Contact

janinelizaduran@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/janinellamzon-ms-agnpc-rn-cen-neabc-575244a7 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

EMR

Healthcare Information Technology
Critical Care

Languages

English (Full Professional) Filipino (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

TNCC

Certified Emergency Nurse
Sigma Theta Tau Nursing Honors
Society

Lean Greenbelt Training

Nurse Executive - Advanced Board Certified (NEA-BC)

Honors-Awards

Nurse Leader of the Year Novice Nurse of the Year

Publications

The impact of an emergency medicine clinical pharmacist on nursing satisfaction

Janine Llamzon MS AGNPc RN CEN NEA-BC

System Director of Nursing and Clinical Operations: Emergency Service Line

Greater New York City Area

Summary

Has Experience in all levels of Emergency Department operations, regulatory requirements, staffing and quality metrics. I have created and implemented safe staffing guidelines and improved multidisciplinary collaboration among all levels of providers. Redesigned nursing informatics within the EMR to shorten triage times, improve compliance and patient safety with required documentation in medication scanning and administration, and restraints. Mentored senior nurses into nursing leadership positions and supported nursing education to improve overall staff knowledge and expertise. In collaboration with medical leadership we reduced patients time to be seen and disposition, reduced AMA's and LWBS, and significantly improved patient satisfaction scores. I possess excellent communication skills with the ability to foster positive relationships with patients, family members, physicians, and other medical professionals. Well-versed in different quality and performance improvement tools to facilitate empirical outcomes. Utilizes mixed media including marketing tools to facilitate change. Innovator. Life long learner. Content creator for QIPI.

Experience

St. Joseph's Health

Director of Nursing and System Operations: Emergency Service line April 2019 - Present (1 year 2 months)

New Jersey

Greater New York Hospital Association Faculty- Clinical Quality Fellowship Program January 2018 - Present (2 years 5 months)

Greater New York Hospital Association and United Hospital Fund

JDL CONSULTING LLC - NJ and Internal Medicine and Geriatrics primary care clinic
BOARD CERTIFIED Adult Geriatric Nurse Practitioner
July 2016 - Present (3 years 11 months)

New Jersey

- primary care NP
- sub-acute patients
- hospice
- long term rehab
- home visits

Our doctor, nurse practitioners and staff are committed to delivering the highest quality care to every one of our patients. We would be honored to be able to care for you and your family today. Respect, diversity, quality and safe patient care.

JDL IIc

The HIP RN - digital content creator July 2016 - February 2020 (3 years 8 months)

Using innovative marketing tools to promote education, quality and safety in healthcare.

Greater New York Nassau Suffolk Organization of Nurse Executives and Leaders

Program Committee Chair May 2018 - May 2019 (1 year 1 month)

Greater New York City Area

Together with other Nursing Leaders, will facilitate and conduct various leadership programs for nurses in the Greater New York region. Engage, Educate, Empower

The Mount Sinai Hospital

Quality Program Manager Patient Safety Innovation, Performance and Process Improvement,

October 2017 - April 2019 (1 year 7 months)

Hybrid role that incorporates quality, education and operations. Designs, strategizes, implements and evaluates measures/processes to facility safe patient care. Excellent problem solving skills. Integrating industrial and human engineering concepts with marketing techniques to influence and change behavior. Transformational leader that understands just culture, systems

thinking and creating solutions that promote habit-forming processes. Utilizes mixed media including videos, social, digital and traditional marketing tools in performance improvement initiatives.

Also involved in hospital wide projects such as

- Editor in Chief Magnet Newsletter
- 2. Adjunct Faculty teaching Quality in the Icahn School of Medicine
- 3. Co-leads insitu simulation

Use of mixed media in unit based PI- national conference May 2018

SBH Health System

10 years 1 month

Nat'l Speaker: Driving Transformation & Innovation through Creativity to Facilitate Culture Change

September 2017 - January 2018 (5 months)

Orlando, Florida Area

Director Of Nursing

April 2016 - October 2017 (1 year 7 months)

Bronx, New York

- Responsible for operational leadership and strategic planning of the Emergency Department. Directs and coordinates curriculum development and oversees the faculty.
- Started barcoding (KBMA) in the ED and reached goal of 85% by 2017 (20% allotted for emergency/stat medications that need bypass of KBMA)
- Leads a group in the creation of a fast-track unit (ongoing)
- Oversees 123 employees 24 hours a day, 7 days a week in a 100K level 1 trauma, STEMI, Stroke Center
- Reduced laboratory errors by 79%. Sustained improvement since commencement in May 2016.
- Leads an interactive bed huddle committee to reduce ED holds
- Created an improved best practice patient flow algorithm for admission to floor, instituting bedside reporting
- Created several EMR tools to improve nursing triage, assessment and documentation, and hand-off.
- Designed a triage algorithm to reduce EMS TAT and disposition.
- Created several quality dashboards to improve medication administration, patient disposition times and EMS release times/throughput
- Created protocols to improve psychiatric patients safety and quality care

- Ensuring that nursing guidelines are followed by writing and updating policies and procedures
- Created and implemented a "Transition to Practice Education Program" for improvement of RN skill and knowledge
- Coordinates with Nursing Education in the improvement of orientation program
- Recruitment and Retention of nurses and auxiliary staff
- Coaches, counsels and monitors nursing care in the department
- Reviews documentation (restraints, moderate sedation, stroke, ESI, nursing assessment, fall)
- Utilizes evidenced based knowledge in the implementation of programs
- Integral member in the implementation of paper charting to EMR

Nat'l Speaker: Throughput and Culture Change Keynote Speaker November 2016 - November 2016 (1 month)

World Congress: ED Throughput

Redistribute physician and nurse workflow to enhance ED throughput and improve patient education and discharge process.

Reducing throughput time is critical to improving patient perceptions and decreasing medical errors attributable to crowding and interruption. We distributed workflow within the ED throughput, strengthen patient education and efficacy and improved patient satisfaction through:

- a. multidisciplinary collaboration
- b. improve resource allocation to enhance patient flow and capacity

Staff nurse/ Senior Nurse/Nurse Manager January 2008 - April 2016 (8 years 4 months)

Emergency room bronx, NY

Greater New York Hospital Association Speaker: Agents of HealthCare Change May 2017 - May 2017 (1 month) United Hospital Fund

https://www.uhfnyc.org/news/881212

St. Joseph Regional Medical Center, Inc. Emergency Room Registered Nurse July 2011 - September 2016 (5 years 3 months) Patterson, NJ Magnet Hospital. Level 2 Trauma Center. Stroke and STEMI centers. Certified Geriatrc ED. DNV accredited.

McCann Worldgroup and Strat works
Account Executive
July 2001 - June 2003 (2 years)
NCR - National Capital Region, Philippines

Education

Case Western Reserve University

Doctorate in Nursing Practice, Nursing Leadership and

Education · (2018 - 2021)

Clinical Quality Fellow

UHF and GNYHA, Quality and High Reliability Organization · (2016 - 2017)

Felician College Nurse Practitioner, Adult Geriatric Nurse Practitioner · (2011 - 2015)

Felician College
Masters of Science , Nursing · (2011 - 2015)

Brokenshire College, Davao
Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Registered Nursing/Registered
Nurse · (2004 - 2006)